hello everyone
today we are going to have a quick look at Steve's Factory Manager
this is a very powerful and useful mod
which can help you solve all sorts of logistic puzzles
but let's start by looking at it block by block
the main block of this mod is the Machine Inventory Manager
this will be the controller of our setups
that will run whatever code we will instruct it with
the other important block we will be using is the inventory cable
which will allow the machine inventory manager to interact with whatever the cable touches
other than those two blocks
there are about a dozen more added by this mod
but we will see those later on when needed
and now after throwing together a bunch of machines
let's see what we can do using SFM
to get started we are going to create our first command
a trigger
by clicking on the first of the buttons on the left
this created a new block for our program
like any other that we will be creating
we can move it around by dragging it from that little square in the top corner
and to make things more understandable
we can also rename our blocks however we like by clicking on the save as icon after opening the block with a left click
this trigger command will be the start of the instruction that our manager will be doing
we can set how often we want that to happen in the interval section
next, we have to connect the commands with the instructions for the manager
the two simplest ones are input and output commands
those two instructions specify from where and which items can be taken and placed by the manager
in the inventory tab, we can select from where the items can be moved
but as you can see
it's not always easy to figure out which chest is which
to avoid confusion, we can make a factory labeler
which will allow us to name inventories
making it easy to spot which one is the chest we want to use
we rename each one of those chests
and then we proceed into selecting a chest to use as input and one to use as output
after selecting an input inventory and an output inventory
we have to connect the block the way we want the program to flow
starting from the start
we take from the A chest and then we drop in the B chest
we can verify the program works by placing some stuff in the chest labeled A and retrieving it in the chest labeled B
however, those two commands have other options we can add
for example, using the items tab, we can filter which items we want to be moved
that is some very basic filtering
but there is more advanced things we can do
if we right click the filtered item
we can set other options
such as how many items should be moved
and one cool feature is that
if we specify an amount as blacklisted
we can keep that amount inside the input inventory
if we select two inputs
the amount to keep will be across both of the chests
meaning only one of the two will keep that amount
we can change that behavior by changing the multi selection settings
if we run the command once per target
we will be able to keep a fixed amount of items in each of the selected inventories
that is something which can be very useful in some automation setups
the next instruction we can use is the condition
as we notice right after adding it
this one has an extra circle
the condition will check inside the specified inventories for the presence of a specified item
depending on the finding result
it will chose one of two possible consecutive instructions
for example, here we can set to follow the old instruction if some cobblestone is present
otherwise, if not cobblestone is present in the chest named A
the program will take a different path
to make the condition check for any item
we can change the detection to match any block
next we have flow blocks
those allow merging or splitting of the program execution flows
liquid input, output and condition are the fluid version of the previously seen blocks
and there is also an energy variant
next, there are Redstone emitters and Redstone conditions
those two instructions will work with two new kind of blocks
Redstone emitter and receiver
and will allow for interacting with external Redstone signals
and using the various option tabs
we can achieve pretty much any kind of Redstone behavior we want
next we have command groups
those instruction blocks will act as a container for many more instruction blocks
we can get in and out of those with the opposite navigation controls
and here we can make a chain of commands act as a single command
saving space in the main program
if we want this group to interact with the main program flow
we can add some command group nodes to do so
making groups of commands has one extra special feature
if we are doing some complex setups with a list of slightly different commands
we can make a group and then duplicate it
finally the last interesting thing I want to show is the camouflage upgrade
this one works with camouflage cables and transforming cables
which we better add to a cable cluster for proper cabling
with that we can change the texture of the cables for better looks
but more importantly
we can change the cable size to allow interacting with blocks that could otherwise be hidden by the cables
and now let's see some examples of usage
in this water plant
we are using SFM to keep exactly 25 liters of hydrochloric acid in the input hatch when the Redstone signal is on
to do so, we check every second the Redstone condition
if there is red stone, then we check if there is already fluid inside the hatch
if so, we do nothing
otherwise, if there is red stone and no fluid inside the hatch
we take from the main tank 25 liters of acid and move it to the hatch
that could have probably been achieved by other means
but it's a good simple example to show what SFM can do and how to use it
one other cool trick we are doing with SFM is on the next water purification plant
where we move an arbitrary item between inventories to keep track of which operation we did last time
as next example, we can automate bacterial vats using SFM
the main objective here is keeping the output hatches half filled
but we also prevent wasting radioactive input materials
to do so we extract everything but 31 buckets of fluid from the output hatches
then we check that we have enough ingredients ready and enough output space available before inserting the radioactive rods to start the process
next we have more complex tasks
such as automating thaumcraft infusion
the program has two parts
which part is run depends on the presence of an item in the middle of the altar
if there is no item in the altar
then we check if we have a crafting order ready in the input chest
if the whole thing has nothing to do
we shut off the world accelerators to save energy
but if we have something ready to be crafted
we move every item on the pedestal
to do so, we have a group with all the insertion commands that will fill the pedestal in a proper order
starting with the first item that is the one supposed to go in the middle of the altar
next we start all the World Accelerators
and pulse the infusion claw to start the process
on the next run of the program
we expect an item to be in the middle of the altar
but to make sure the process is complete
we also make sure there are no other items waiting for the process
if so we wait one extra half second to make sure everything stabilized
then we proceed into retrieving the finished item
and we also shut off the World Accelerators
if you want to see more examples
you can check my GTNH season 2
bye bye
大家好
今天我们来看看SFM
这是一个非常强大和有用的mod
可以帮助你解决各种物流难题
但是让我们一个方块一个方块来
此mod的主要方块是工厂管理器
这将是产线物流的控制器
它将运行我们给他写的代码
我们将使用的另一个重要方块是工厂线缆
这将允许工厂管理器与线缆接触的任何东西进行交互
除了那两个方块
这个mod还添加了十几个方块
但我们稍后会在需要时介绍它们
现在在组装了一堆机器之后
让我们看看SFM可以做些什么
首先，我们将创建我们的第一个指令
触发器
通过单击左侧的第一个按钮
这为我们的程序创建了一个新的模块
就像我们将创建的任何其他模块一样
我们可以通过拖动左上角的小方块来移动它
为了让事情更容易理解
我们也可以在左键单击打开模块
更改名称，并单击另存为图标重命名模块
这个触发指令将是处理器将要执行的指令的开始
我们可以在间隔部分设置处理器工作的时间间隔
接下来，我们必须连接给管理器的指令
最简单的两个指令是输入和输出
这两个指令指定了管理器
可以从哪里取走或者放置哪些物品
在库存选项卡中，我们可以选择可以从哪取出物品
但如你所见
弄清楚哪个箱子是哪个并不总是容易的
为避免混淆，我们可以制作工厂贴标器
这将使我们能够命名库存
让我们更容易发现哪个是我们想要使用的箱子
我们给每个箱子重新命名
然后我们继续选择一个箱子作为输入，一个作为输出
选择输入库存和输出库存后
我们必须按照我们希望程序执行的顺序连接模块
从触发器开始
我们从A类箱子中取出，然后放入B类箱子中
我们可以通过"在标为A的箱子里放一些东西
并在标为B的箱子里取回它"来验证程序有正常工作
但是，这两个指令还有其他可选项
例如，使用物品选项卡，我们可以过滤要移动的物品
这是一些非常基本的过滤
但我们可以做更高级的事情
如果我们右键单击过滤后的物品
我们可以设置其他选项
例如应该移动多少物品
一个很酷的功能是
如果我们给黑名单物品指定数量
我们可以将该数量的物品保留在输入库存中
如果我们选择两个输入
要保留的数量将作用于两个箱子的整体
这意味着两个箱子中只有一个会保留这个数量的物品
我们可以通过更改多选设置来改变这种行为
如果我们给每个目标都运行一次指令
我们将能够在每个选定的库存中保留固定数量的物品
这在某些自动化设置中非常有用
我们可以使用的下一个指令是条件模块
正如我们在添加后立即注意到的那样
这个多了一个圆圈
条件模块将检查指定库存中是否存在指定物品
取决于库存返回的结果
它将从两个可能的连续指令中选择一个
例如，如果存在一些圆石
我们可以在这里设置为遵循旧指令
否则，如果在A的箱子中没有圆石存在
程序将走上不同的道路
要检查库存中是否存在物品，无论种类
我们可以更改检测以匹配任何方块
接下来是流程模块
这些允许合并或拆分程序执行流
液体输入、输出和条件模块是先前看到的模块的流体版本
还有类似的能量模块
接下来是红石发射器和红石条件模块
这两个指令将和两种新方块搭配工作
红石发射器和接收器
并允许与外部红石信号交互
通过使用各种选项卡
我们几乎可以实现任何我们想要的红石行为
接下来我们有指令组
指令组将充当更多指令模块的容器
我们可以通过点击边栏的左箭头进出指令组
在这里，我们可以把一系列指令封装成单个指令
以节省主程序空间
如果我们想让这个程序组与主程序流程交互
我们可以添加一些指令组节点来执行此操作
制作指令组有一个额外的特殊功能
如果我们正在使用稍微不同的指令列表进行一些复杂的设置
我们可以做一个组然后复制它
最后我想展示的有趣东西是伪装升级
伪装升级必须和"伪装方块"以及"伪装方块-变换"搭配工作
我们最好将其添加到集线器中以进行适当的布线
有了它，我们可以改变线缆的贴图，让它变得更美观
但更重要的是
我们可以改变线缆尺寸，来与被线缆遮挡的方块交互
现在让我们看一些用法示例
在这个净化水厂里
当有红石信号时，我们使用SFM保持输入舱有25L盐酸
为此，我们每秒检查红石条件
如果有红石信号，那么检查仓室内是否已经有液体
如果是这样，我们什么都不做
否则，如果有红石并且仓室没有液体
我们从主罐中取出25L盐酸并将其移至仓室
这套流程可以通过其他方式实现
但这是一个展示SFM能做什么
以及如何使用它的好例子
在SFM中用的另一个很酷的技巧在下一个净水厂中
我们在库存之间移动一个标志物来确定我们上次执行的操作
下一个例子是用SFM自动化细菌培养缸
这里的主要目标是保持输出仓半满
但我们也要防止浪费放射性输入材料
为此，我们从输出仓提取除了31桶液体之外的所有东西
然后我们在插入"能够启动配方的放射性棒"之前
检查我们是否有足够的原材料和可用的输出空间
接下来我们有更复杂的任务
例如自动化神秘注魔
该程序有两个部分
要运行哪部分取决于祭坛中间是否存在物品
如果祭坛里没有东西
然后我们检查输入箱中是否准备好了订单原料
如果系统没有要执行的任务
我们关闭世界加速器以节省能量
但如果我们有东西可以制作
我们把所有物品移动到基座上
为此，我们有一个能够按正确顺序
填充基座的插入指令的指令组
从第一件应该放在祭坛中间的物品开始
接下来我们启动所有的世界加速器
并向注魔爪输出红石脉冲以开始注魔
在程序的下一次运行中
我们预计有一件物品在祭坛中间
但要确保注魔已经完成
我们还要确定没有其他物品等待处理
如果是这样，我们多等半秒钟以确保一切稳定
然后我们继续取出完成的物品
关闭世界加速器
如果你想看更多的例子
你可以看看我的GTNH第二季
拜拜
（这时候圆石改为任何物品都能达到这个效果）